Kyle Langford

Design + Code

kylelangford.com

203-803-6120 kyle.langford@gmail.com Boston, MA

HELLO!

I am a Designer and Frontend Developer whose focus is creating easy-to-use interfaces and writing clean, human-readable code. As a leader and mentor, I have experience communicating ideas, developing team strategies, and managing client expectations. I have a positive attitude and enjoy bringing ideas to life. I am passionate about learning new skills and evolving my process.

EDUCATION

Northeastern University Boston, MA

Bachelor of Science Dual Major in Graphic Design and Multimedia, Minor in Computer Animation.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Interaction Designer — Brunello, Inc.

March 2012 - Current

Involved in all phases of projects from strategy and research to implementation. Provides design leadership, quick prototyping and wireframing. Ensures the interactions, flow, and the overall experience of the product works well for the user. Produces standards-driven, production quality frontend code.

COMPETENCIES

Experience Design Frontend Development Information Architecture Interface Design Prototyping Wireframing

Freelance Agency Partner — Raskyl Collective, LLC.

June 2011 - Current

Co-owner of Digital Agency. Oversees business development and provides technical leadership. Designs and develops user-friendly web solutions, email marketing, branding, and Drupal/Wordpress managed websites. Past clients include Drizly, GasBuddy, Harvard, Unreal Candy, Latitude Sports Clubs, Mass. Emergency Nurses Association and more.

TECHNOLOGY

Apache
AngularJS, Angular
Drupal CMS
Git (Version Control)
HTML, CSS
JavaScript ES6
Linux
MySQL
Node.js / NPM
PHP

Lead Web Designer — Questex Media, LLC.

November 2010 - March 2012

Led company design meetings and developed team initiatives and strategies. Worked closely with the marketing group to design websites and landing pages for various B2B industries. Implemented frontend theming solutions for Drupal powered websites.

INTERESTS

Accessibility
Applications Development
Animation
Design Systems
Product Design
CSS Frameworks

Web Designer and Developer — WebGURU, Northeastern University

April 2009 - December 2010

Launched web platform to help students navigate the hurdles of undergraduate research and connect with opportunities. Produced a series of educational videos on professional meetings and conferences. Showcased at the Northeastern University Research & Scholarship Expo 2010.

Project Designer — Wojciechowski Design

July 2008 - April 2009

Designed wayfinding and signage systems for the Cambridge and Crandall Public Library. Art directed typography, photography, and visual styles. Created 2d and 3d visualizations to present work to clients. Drafted artwork for fabrication, including designing mounts, materials selection, and placement.